Now we're on to the next step.
Now we're going to prepare one of the condiments to go with our salmon and today that's rice.
Now there's many different kinds of rice.
Every country in the world practically grows rice where there's any kind of a warm tropical climate.
Today, I've decided to choose jasmine rice.
Jasmine rice is a Thai rice.
Comes from Thailand.
It's a little more flavorful.
It's kind of the, part of the family of sweet rices.
It's a whole grain rice as you can see here.
What's nice about jasmine rice is it's got nice flavor.
It cooks relatively easily and evenly.
First thing we need to do is take our rice and rinse it.
It's important to always rinse your rice.
Because when you're cooking rice, you want to remove any of the excess starch that may have occurred when the rice has been rubbing against itself in shipment.
Just going to set that aside and let it drain.
In the mean time, in our pot we're going to add an equal amount of water.
With jasmine rice, it's one part water to one part rice.
I'm cooking a cup and a half of rice, so I need a cup and a half of boiling water.
And we take our element, turn it up to max, let the water boil.
In the mean time let's make sure that we have drained our rice thoroughly.